#### **NAGA DEEPTHI THOLU**

Email Id: <a href="mailto:nagadeepthi.t@gmail.com">nagadeepthi.t@gmail.com</a>
.Net Full stack Developer

## **ABOUT ME**

A highly motivated .Net Full Stack Developer with 15+ years of experience in designing, developing, and implementing web-based applications using .Net technologies. Seeking a challenging position in a dynamic organization where I can utilize my technical skills and knowledge to contribute to the success of the team while constantly learning and growing in my career.

#### **Experience Summary**

- Have a total of 15+ years of programming experience in developing web/Desktop applications using ASP.NET, C#, VB.NET, ASP.Net core and Java.
- Experience working with Boeing's Airline customers for Reliability data acquisition from the year 2008 to current.
- Technical Expertise in Client/Server Architecture, Object Oriented Programming and Web applications.
- Have experience in technologies like AJAX and MVC architecture and micro services.
- Have experience in all the phases of the project Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC)
- Proficient in Relational Database application development using SQL Server 2012/2015/2018,
   MS Access, Oracle, Teradata, DB2 and working with Entity framework.
- o Experience in converting different file formats like DAT/word/PDF/xlsx to XML.
- Experience in developing XSD schemas and XSL Style sheets
- o Experience in generating graphs by using chart controls and SSRS services and SSIS packages and Power BI.
- Involved in implementing n-tier architecture.
- Written consumable API code to integrate with enterprise applications and get the live/synced data. Also written an exposable Web API's.
- Developed and deployed scalable cloud-based applications on the Azure platform using .NET Core, ASP.NET, and Azure services such as Azure Functions, Azure Cosmos DB, Azure App Service, and Azure SQL Database and Azure DevOps.
- Utilized Azure functions and serverless computing to create event-driven architectures with
   MongoDB triggers, enabling real-time processing and data updates based on changes in the database.
- Leveraged Azure Functions to build serverless microservices and event-driven architectures, enabling scalable and cost-effective solutions.

- Exhibited extensive experience in using Jira.
- Used Entity Framework Database First Approach for creating database Models.
   Designed and developed a front-end widget using ReactJS and Expertise in building Components by using React and making them scalable as reusable components.

0

- o Programming experience in languages like ASP.NET, **ASP.NET core**, C#, VB.NET, Java, XML, HTML, JavaScript, Angular JS, ReactJS.
- o Implemented UI and middle wear and database functionality for .NET Core API projects
- o implemented JWT token-based authentication to secure the ASP.NET Core Web API
- o Have hands on experience in developing web services (SOAP and Restful) using .NET core .
- o Excellent communication and presentation skills as well as vibrant team player, also comfortable in working individually. Excellent work ethics, self-motivated and quick learner.
- o Knowledge on Springboot with Micro services and Spring Cloud.
- Exposure on Google Cloud and AWS with a proven track record of designing and implementing cost-effective and reliable infrastructure solutions using services EC2, S3, and Lambda.
- Implemented Rest APIs based on architecture frameworks and guidelines using AWS. Prepared functional specifications and test data.
- Worked on a several reliability Data extraction projects to pull ISDP data for various Airline
  Operators like United Airlines, Singapore Airlines, Lion Air, Malindo Airlines, NLH Airlines,
  LATAM Airlines that have various M&E systems like TRAX, Maintenix, AMOS, AMICOS, SAP
  and Snowflake through Boeing.
- Have skills on MuleSoft and actively working on project for Boeing RDM team at Seal beach,
   California.
- Hands on experience of 1.5 years in developing Web APIs using MuleSoft for building Restful API's and Dataweave for transformation related to Boeing customers ISDP Data provided in various formats and API testing through Postman, API management and Monitoring.
- Proficient in writing MsTests , NUnit test cases for .Net Core projects and MUnit for Mulesoft projects

# **Certifications:**

- SAFe Agilest certification in the year 2020
- Microsoft certified Azure Fundamentals Microsoft, May2024 AZ900
- Salesforce certified Mulesoft Developer 1, Salesforce, May2024

# **Educational Qualifications**

 Bachelor of Technology (Computer Science and Engineering) from J.B Institute of Engineering and Technology (year 2005), affiliated to Jawaharlal Nehru Technological University, Hyderabad, India.

# **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Languages	C#.Net, VB.Net, C, LINQ, Java, XML, XSD, Python
Web Technologies	ASP.NET CORE, ASP.NET MVC, ADO.NET, Web API, Web Services, WCF
RDBMS and Databases	SQL Server, NOSQL, Teradata, Oracle
Scripting/Markup Languages	JavaScript, jQuery, React JS, Angular JS, Ajax, JSON, XML, HTML5, CSS3, PowerShell, Data weave
Cloud Technologies	Azure, MuleSoft, AWS
IDE Tools	Visual Studio, VS Code, SSDT, NetBeans, Spring Test Suite, Eclipse
Source Control Tools	GitHub, Team Foundation Server (TFS), Visual Source Safe (VSS), SVN
API Testing Tools	Soap UI, Postman, Swagger
Unit Testing	MS Tests, NUnit, XUnit
Methodologies	Agile and Waterfall
Web Servers	IIS 7.5 / 6.0, SharePoint Portal 2010, JBoss, Tomcat
ESB	MuleSoft

# **Work Experience**

Current Employer- Cyient Inc, USA

Client: The Boeing Company

May 2023- Current

#### **Job Duties**

- Customer interactions and updating status to Business team
- Participated in Daily SCRUM meetings and updating TFS backlog and sprints
- Requirements gathering and analysis and team management at Offshore.
- Development activities
- o Presenting Work requests to Business team for enhancements/change requests approval.
- Perform Unit testing
- Maintenance and monitoring of 15 Desktop/Web Applications deployed at Customer locations
- o Monitoring of prod autosys jobs and involved in code deployments to Dev, Tst, PROD and UAT regions.
- Writing Scripts, Stored Procedures, Triggers, Indexes and scheduled Jobs.
- Performing Unit Testing, Integration Testing, Client, Server-side Validation, Sessions and Caching data to local storage.
- o Performing vulnerability scans using coverity for the source code and implementing code fixes

## **Experience Details**

Employer: Cyient Ltd 2006-Current

## Project #1

Project Name: Boeing Reliability Data Management API -MuleSoft | Aug 2023- Current

Client Name: Boeing, USA

Environment: Mulesoft, Anypoint Platform, Anypoint Studio, SQL Server, Message Queue

#### **Description:**

The purpose of RDM SPEC2K API is to enable Airline operators to use Boeing API's and submit Reliability data in SPEC2K format that provides operators with instant feedback on the data. This application also helps address operator-specific issues, benefiting member airlines and Boeing's ability to support its customers effectively by providing access to Analytics provided by Tableau cloud. Worked on Experience, System and Process APIs and monitoring for Component Removals module.

API's are categorized in to Fleet, Logs and Parts

Following are the different modules:

**SPEC2K Standard API:** Allows Airline Operators to consume SPEC2K standard API and to submit data to Being using Daily or Monthly

**SPEC2K Summary API:** Allows Airline Operators to get the summary of the data provided for all data subjects for validation

**ISDP excel API:** API built to process the ISDP template format Excels

**ISDP excel API 2.**0: API that takes minimum required fields in the format of Json and performs validation and publishes the message to XML Subscriber when Then transforms the data and stores in SPEC database tables.

SPEC2K SPLIT API for Monthly huge XMLs: Allows Airlines to submit payload >10 MB

For a data subject and the payload is split based on business rules and is stored Boeing

ARDB and SPEC databases for further processing.

## Project # 2

Project Name: Events Formatting Tool 2.0 | Jan2023- Current

Client Name: Boeing, USA

**Environment:** .Net core, C#, Teradata, SSIS Package, React, Rest API, Web API Services, Rabbit MQ, TFS GIT, jQuery, LINQ, ASP.Net MVC, Entity Framework, IIS 10.0, CSS 4, HTML 5, Azure

#### **Description:**

EFT 2.0 is a web application developed for enrichment for Aircraft Schedule Interruptions data for Monthly and Daily operators. This application contains work flow management that provides provision for records assignment to the SI processing team, tracking the status, enrichment and providing downline reports to the users. The processed data is saved to Boeing OLTP Teradata region which is later refreshed to MART region.

Following are the different modules:

**Work Assignment:** Allows manager to assign the records to individuals for processing Enrichment: user performs the enrichment of the data foe the assigned records

**Events History:** Allows user/admin to verify the history of the data processed for each operator and reporting period.

**Enrichment:** Users review each record and update Chargeability based on READI rules and assign ASN number. The enriched data is saved to ARMS OLTP region and further moves to MART database during refresh.

**User Management:** Allows admin to add/update user details

Project #3

**Project Name: Boeing Data Ingestion Project (BDIP)** 

**Duration:** AUG 2021- 2023

Client Name: Boeing, USA

**Environment:** .Net core, C#, SQL Server 2016, SSIS Package, SSRS, SSAS, XML, React Js, Rest API, Web API Services, Rabbit MQ, TFS GIT, JQuery, LINQ, ASP.Net MVC, Entity Framework, IIS 10.0,

CSS 4, HTML 5

Database: SQL Server, Teradata

Worked on BDIP (Boeing Data Ingestion Process) which is used to transform data submitted by data providers (operators and suppliers) in various file formats into a structured format by creating appropriate mappings to each file format from each provider. Process also includes Translation services to translate from Chinese language to English prior to the transformation process. Application notifies users for any missing/Invalid input files from operators. Developed User Interface Application, Improved data quality, performed Performance enhanced Techniques and built services

Project # 4

Project Name: Boeing ISDP Adapter Application | JAN 2018- JUL 2021

Client Name: Boeing, USA

Environment: MVC, Angular Js, Java Script, HTML, XML, XSD, ASP.NET

Database: SQL Server, Teradata

Description:

ISDP Adapter is a Web application developed in Java using MVC architecture. The purpose of this project is to provide a single solution for Boeing to process reliability

format and convert to Standard XML format that follows SPEC2000 standards for all reliability data subjects.

Application provided users to perform configuration for each ROC.

Provision to process the data using Data Conversion Screen.

Provision to update the configuration to Insert, Update, Delete.

Provides functionality to add OPRs for each ROC and data subject wise configurations and generate Log Reports based on the selected Date range and ROC.

Application has the following Modules:

Configuration, Data Conversion, Log Reports and Scheduler which processed inputs 24X7

## Responsibilities:

- Involved in all stages of Software development life cycle including Design, Analysis, development, Implementation, testing and support.
- Worked in Agile Methodology to meet timelines with quality deliverables. Created Business Logic Layer & Data Access Layers to implement the MVC architecture.
- Involved in enhancing the application for client's requirement based on the market demand.
- Preparing database objects
- Involved in Unit testing and UAT testing
- Production monitoring and support

# Project #6

Boeing, Seattle, WA

**Communication and Status Tracker (CAST)** 

**Duration:** FEB 2014- SEP 2016

Environment: Microsoft .NET MVC 4.0 framework, Entity Framework, JQuery /Java script, SQL

Server 2008 R2, SSRS and SSIS

The web based Communication & status tracker tool application is used to track all aspects of customer relationship from the time they are first contacted to the time they are fully integrated. Tool collects information like airline contacts, distribution lists, PIA sign dates, data integration status, data submittal formats, details about the Airline MRO, notes about important communication with an airline.

Responsibilities:

- Extensive involvement in all stages of Software development life cycle including Design, Analysis, development, Implementation, testing and support.
- Worked in Agile Methodology to meet timelines with quality deliverables Created Business Logic Layer & Data Access Layers to implement the MVC architecture.
- Involved in enhancing the application for client's requirement based on the market demand.

#### Project #5

**Project Name: SPEC2000 Data Conversion Application** (Same project implemented for various Airlines like Continental Airlines, Singapore Airlines, LAN Airlines, United Airlines, Malindo Airlines, Lion Air, Norwegian Longhaul Airlines, Hainan Airlines and Pratt & Whitney Supplier that is customized to use different M&E databases like Oracle, SAP, SQL Server, Excel, DB2, Teradata, Snowflake) | APR 2008- MAY 2016

This project is a recurrent project implementing with multiple airlines based on their availability and acceptance to onsite locations. This project is started in Apr'08 and continued till May'16 where I have supported multiple airlines as onsite-offshore model during this period.

**Environment:** C#.net, XML, XSD, LINQ, Web Services

Databases: SQL Server, Teradata, SSIS, Db2, Oracle, Snowflake, SAP, Excel, MS Access

## Description:

The purpose of this project is to extract Aircraft Reliability data Compliant to ATA SPEC2000 Chapter 11 for operator specific M&E database to standard SPEC2000 XML.

The SPEC2000 Data Conversion tool for each Airline is developed using .Net/Java technologies. The application is developed for Hours and Cycles, LRU Removals, Logbook, Aircraft Events, Shop Findings, Piece parts, Scheduled Maintenance and Service Bulletin modules where the application extracts data every day for all Boeing Aircraft models. The application is developed as a GUI application and a Scheduler application where the application executes at a specific time every day for all models and also transmits the XML files to Boeing through automated Manages File Transfer System (MFTS).

Designed and developed web pages, business rules framework using C#, Bootstrap, MVC,
 Entity Framework, HTML, JavaScript, JQuery, AJAX, and Sql Server.

- Implemented the ORM models like Entity Framework.
- Involved in configuring Entity Framework and used EF database first approach by creating tables first and then updated edmx file. Also using log4net write the exception messages into database.
- Implementation of client-side validations using JQuery, java Script and MVC Validation implemented at Controller level.
- Used Bootstrap for creating responsive web design.
- Involved in writing and managing software requirement, test cases and data flow diagrams of the Project.
- Used the ADO.NET objects like the Dataset, Data reader, and Command objects to access the database.
- Created Entity Data models and developed stored procedures using SQL Server 2008.
- Writing database components to access database using ADO.NET, LINQ and Entity Framework.
- Developed SSIS packages to import data from source database tables to application tables.
- Developed reports using SQL Server Reporting Services (SSRS)
  - Used TFS for Version Control.